Any
[music]
chance we get to speak with John
Kuryaku, we say yes. Uh we talked to him
a little over a year ago and it was one
of our best conversations we had. Um
although we got many comments saying how
we were interrupting him and when I saw
it render we really were uh what was
unbeknownst to most everybody was that
we were having huge technical issues and
so I was hearing him double in my ears.
It was hard to understand when there was
silence or when he was done talking. And
so this time we went to him in person.
We didn't want to have any of those
issues and so we went to DC and we got
to sit down with him in person and I
think it was one of our best
conversations we've ever had. Um in the
last year he has just gone parabolic in
his fame. Uh he was on Tucker Carlson,
he was on Danny Jones, Sean Ryan, Joe
Rogan, uh and now he's on the Austin
Matt podcast. So I'm really grateful we
get to talk to him. I appreciate his
perspective as a DC insider ex CIA
whistleblower. He kind of knows how the
game is played. I appreciate his gut
checks on sort of what's going on. So,
we get into geopolitics and we really
give him a lot of room to talk in this
one. Um, and just uh I appreciate his
perspective and I try and learn from him
every time I'm with him. So, thank you
so much for watching. Like and subscribe
if you haven't. We're doing, you know,
we're still growing and uh we want to
keep doing this. So, all right. Hope you
enjoy it. Welcome to the Austin and Matt
podcast.
>> John Kuryaku, welcome to the show.
>> Thank you. Thanks for having me.
>> It seems like the US government might be
destroying itself. What do you What do
you think about that? Is that true?
>> I I think it's true. And it's not This
is not a partisan issue. The Democrats,
the Republicans, there's no no light
between them. We have, Forgive me for
repeating myself, but I say this all the
time. Our defense budget is bigger than
the next eight largest countries
combined,
>> right? That's not tenable over the long
term.
>> And so
>> year after year, year after year after
year,
>> we're like eight to 10 times more than
the other eight combined.
>> Yeah,
>> that's crazy.
>> It's crazy. It's crazy. And then we
wonder why we have bridges that are
falling into the rivers below them. Why
our airports are [__] and embarrassing.
Why our interstate highways are, you
know, pocked with potholes and they're
impassible. Why our our hospitals are
all in need of of upgrades cuz we spend
all the money on weapons
>> and all these other countries have great
hospitals, great roads, great bridges is
because they don't spend as much on
military.
>> That's right.
>> We're sitting here not too far from
Foggy Bottom where a lot of the agency
headquarters are. Do you think there is
a lot of the money going into DC that
doesn't need to be right now?
>> Oh yeah. Oh, listen. Before 911, uh the
the highest concentration of
millionaires per capita in the United
States was in Silicon Valley in Northern
California. Post 911, it's right here in
Washington.
>> Yeah, that's not a good sign.
>> A lot of people got very rich from 911.
>> What What is China thinking about this
right now? Oh, the Chinese know, the
Chinese have a far longer term outlook
on life than we do. Um, and it's because
our presidents have four-year terms.
>> That's right.
>> And the Chinese are just there forever.
And so, they know that they can outweigh
us. They know that we're going to get to
a tipping point one of these days where
we just can't pay the interest on the
national debt anymore.
>> It's pretty currency related, right? I
mean, a country is its currency. That's
how I like to think about it. And if if
you can't sustain the currency, the
country falls.
>> And that's why a unified bricks currency
is such a threat to us.
>> Totally.
>> You know, it's just in the discussion
stages right now and the US is going to
do everything it can to make sure it
never ever happens. But, you know, do we
have that authority over the long term?
Is it really up to us to tell the
Chinese, the Russians, the Indians, the
Brazilians, the South Africans, the
South Koreans, the Iranians, no, you
can't do that because it's not good for
us. I think they're going to laugh at
us.
>> I think they're going to proceed.
Anyways,
>> India's been buying a lot of gold. I
know Russia's been buying a lot of gold.
It seems like they're going to be in a
position to have a gold back currency.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know if we have that much gold,
to be honest. It's kind of hard to tell.
>> They they just tell us to take their
word for it. I mean, I never met anybody
that's been inside Fort Knox and has
seen the gold. And I've traveled in
some, you know, rarified circles over
the years. The government just says we
have to just believe them. Well, they
always say it's just it's a security
risk because I remember Elon, he said he
was going to go in and stream it on X
and it never happened and because it's
always a security risk. We don't want
people seeing the doors and the locks
and and it's it's it's just plausible
enough to go Yeah. Okay. But like
>> but if no one ever gets to see it ever,
we've this has happened in history
before and when I don't know, bring it
out, show it, and then bring it back in.
I mean, do something where we don't see
all the security, but you can bring it
in the yard. just turn it on the turn on
the camera when you're there in front of
the gold. You don't have to see the the
doors and the spin locks and and the
cameras and all that stuff.
>> So So what does the US have going for it
right now? Like like what are what are
our because if we're if our back's up
against a corner right now, like what do
we have going for us? What's good?
>> 12 aircraft carrier battle groups.
>> I mean that's that's kind of the the
display of our of our might is in our
carrier battle groups. Um, we still do
have the world's go-to reserve currency.
Uh, just about every oil purchase is
still made in dollars. No matter who's
doing the buying and who's doing the
selling, it's all
>> Is that the case even for Russia?
>> No, the Russians are bartering a lot of
it. And then they're they're taking
rubles at whatever the international
rate happens to be. They've they've
proven to be far more resilient than we
gave them credit for being. Um the
foreign minister Sergey Lavrov said uh
right after
the invasion of of Ukraine, he said that
that the Russians were surprised at the
quickness with which the United States
imposed very serious sanctions. And then
6 months later he said the Russians were
surprised at the quickness with which
they were able to come out from under
the sanctions.
Is there something? Is there a deal
going to be struck between Putin and
Trump? Do you think? I I've heard about
this peace board.
>> You know, the Russians, there's no
incentive for the Russians to make a
deal cuz they're winning
>> and they don't need us. They're pretty
self-sufficient from a resource
perspective.
>> Yeah, very much so.
>> At least don't need anything.
>> They've got oil, they've got gas,
they've got gold, they've got everything
they need.
>> Do you need us? Do you think UK Ukraine
will become like Afghanistan where we've
dumped a bunch of resources and weapons
and eventually we're just going to
abandon it and we're going to have
billions of dollars of weapons sitting
there?
>> I think that it's not going to it's not
going to become the no man's land that
Afghanistan has become. But yeah, I
think what's going to end up happening
is it's going to be a rump state. It's
not going to look like it looks on the
maps right now. They've they've lost
Donetsk and Luhansk. They've they're
going to lose um Carke.
Uh I I wouldn't bet money that, you
know, Crimea changes hands again. And
even Odessa, the Russians just said
what, three weeks ago, four weeks ago
that they want Odessa. That's a serious
red line for the rest of the world. But
who's going to stop them? We're not
willing to commit troops. It would be an
act of war and it would put Russia at
war with NATO which is, you know, by
definition it's World War II.
>> Are we really willing to die for
Ukraine? I don't think so. I heard from
Tom Billu that uh any nation that's been
over their GD their debt to GDP ratio
has been over 130%. Has never not gone
to war in 18 months after hitting that
except for Japan who basically they were
an exception and we're quickly
approaching the 13%.
>> We're in the 20s right now. I just
looked at
a couple of days ago. Yeah.
>> Yeah. And they say it's in the next year
or so we're going to hit it or so. Um
does that it seems like war is a
byproduct of
>> Yeah.
>> poor and poor currency
>> because war supercharges an economy and
you can inflate your way out of debt.
>> You turn money into noise as they say.
>> Yeah. That's right. I'll tell you what
really worries me
>> is um
as a country and again this is not
partisan either. We just seem to be
willing to do Israel's bidding
>> whenever they whenever they demand it.
>> Why?
>> I don't know.
>> The only explanation I have, and it's a
kooky one, is that they have alien
technology. Like I like I don't I lit
they they they have something that's
like we have an ace. They have some card
that they just can show and everyone's
like, "Wow, we just
>> But I you know what I think it is
realistically though?
>> We we said a moment ago that the Chinese
have a long view. The Israelis have a
long view, too. in in the 1950s, um,
Apac was formed and it was nobody ever
heard of Apac. It was this little teeny
tiny, you know, lobbying group. It
really didn't mean anything in
Washington. And then they started
raising money and more money and more
money and more money. And then in 1969,
um, Richard Nixon
guaranteed Israeli security. No
president before had done that. He
guaranteed Israeli security. So all of a
sudden,
we're committed to making sure that
Israel is as strong and secure as it can
possibly be. Well, that's not the the
Israeli definition of security and the
American definition are two different
things. And it's not always in American
interests to align with the Israeli
definition.
What's the Israeli definition?
>> That we have to create
a sense of constant chaos in the Middle
East.
>> Because when countries are fighting
themselves, that means they're not
fighting Israel.
>> That's their peace. Is everyone else
battling?
>> That's right. I'll give you a couple of
examples.
>> Is that true? If it goes all to peace,
everybody will turn at Israel and look
at them.
>> No.
>> Oh, it's it's a narrative.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, it didn't seem true.
>> No, it's absolutely not true. No. Where
do we even start with this? So
in 2003, we were getting ready to attack
Iraq.
And
three or four days before the invasion,
the Israelis discreetly came to us and
they said, "We want in on this." And we
said, "Absolutely not.
Absolutely not. You can't have anything
to do with it. If you do, every Arab
country in the alliance is going to drop
out.
the next day. Well, I Iraq in its
western desert has um
uh big power pylons, right? Because
nobody lives in the western desert. So,
they were they were exporting some
electricity to Jordan. They were
exporting a little bit to Syria. So,
these are three-legged pylons, which are
cheaper to build than four-legged
pylons. And then two days before the
invasion, these pylons just started
tipping over and then the next one would
tip and then the next one would tip. And
I remember the deputy director of the
CIA saying, "Fucking Israelis just can't
stay out of it
cuz they they didn't think that we were
going to create enough chaos in Iraq and
they thought we might as well just take
out the entire electrical grid, too. Why
not?"
You know,
>> can you explain to me what happened in
Iran when we bombed the nuclear
facility? Did how were there first of
all, how are there no casualties? I just
can't imagine. I see.
>> I have I have a theory.
>> Did we? Yeah.
>> I think we warned him in advance.
>> Yeah, we must have, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We're coming in. You got three
days.
>> Do that.
>> Yeah.
>> Going back a little bit, um, you know,
the Israelis bombed, uh, Thrron, right?
The Israelis have a very very
sophisticated program to take out
military leadership and nuclear
scientists. They've killed everybody.
They took out literally the entire
military leadership. The 12 top
generals, every one of them's dead. And
they did that by targeting their cell
phones. what they did. There are two
million
um Afghan refugees in in Iran, but
because they're refugees and they're not
documented, they can't get any benefits,
including food, medical care, housing.
So, they're literally just living in the
streets.
So the Israelis discreetly went in and
said, "Listen, we'll give you $100 a
month if you tell us what time the
general leaves that apartment every
morning and which way he's going." And
so you just recruit all of these
homeless, destitute refugees, give them
$100 or $50, at least they'll be able to
eat for the month. And then you're
collecting volumes of intelligence.
And so they took out the entire military
leadership.
The Iranians realized what was happening
and so they forbade all general officers
from carrying cell phones. Right? The
Israelis went in with a second wave and
killed the next wave of generals. How
did they do that? It never occurred to
the Iranians to tell the generals
bodyguards that they can't carry cell
phones. Of course.
>> And so they just targeted the bodyguard
cell phones. It was as easy as that.
>> They kill nuclear scientists in Iran,
either by having assassins on the
ground, which they do, or with drones,
which they also use, and then they kill
them when they go around the world to
attend seminars or university classes or
whatever. You either recruit them or
kill them if they refuse the
recruitment. So they've they've beaten
the Iranians that way.
Then
the Iranians, which was my original
point, the Iranians, to save face, they
just took it on the chin from the
Israelis. They're going to have to
retaliate, but they don't want the
Israelis to use nukes against them. So,
they tell us, "Listen, we're going to
send like 700 drones. They're slow
motion drones, and they don't have
missiles on them. They're suicide
drones. They just crash into the
building. They have explosives and they
blow up. So tell the Israelis, we're
going to send these drones. So we tell
the Israelis, the Iranians are going to
attack you. They're going to send these
drones. The Iranians launched their
drones. They're subsonic. So it took
them like six hours to cross Iraq and
Jordan. The Israelis were ready for
them. And then they shot all but I think
it was like 11. 11 made it through or
seven made it through. whatever it was,
maybe it was seven, made it through.
That's valuable intelligence. So, the
Iron Dome isn't so airtight as everybody
thinks it is. But anyway, one guy got
killed in Tel Aviv, six people got
injured. No big deal. But then the
Israelis attacked again and the Iranians
are like, "Okay, well, now we have to
retaliate again because they've attacked
us and they can't look weak to their own
people." So, they start launching
missiles. Now, the Iranians, like the
Russians and the Chinese, have
supersonic missiles. We don't. Ours are
still in the testing phase. So, their
missiles can break the sound barrier,
and they're much much more difficult to
handle. And several got through.
So, then the Israelis bombed
Gutter
and killed the chief negotiator for
Hamas. Now, Gutter is a major non-NATO
ally, right? We are compelled by treaty
to defend Gutter. So, what do we do?
We're going to bomb Israel. Can't do
that. So, we give the Israelis a stern
talking to and we make them apologize
and we look like fools for allowing it
to happen. Um, and then the Iranians
uh start worrying that we're going to
bomb their nuclear facilities. Now,
here's where things changed in terms of
American policy.
Literally, every Israeli prime minister,
going back to, you know, Reagan,
when he would come to the United States,
he would say, "You got to bomb Iran. You
got to bomb Iran. You got to bomb Iran."
And every single president said, "No,
we're not going to bomb Iran for you
until this president."
Now, the rumor is
that the reason why President Trump
decided to bomb Iran is because
Netanyahu told him, "If you don't, we're
going to bomb them, but we're going to
use nukes."
And so, we bombed the Iranians with a
bunker buster, the a Moab, you know,
mother of all bombs.
>> Um,
>> just so the Israelis wouldn't use
nuclear weapons. Holy cow.
But the Iranians survived. You know,
Iran is a gigantic country. It has 92
million people. And public opinion is
not as deeply divided as the Israelis
want people to believe. You know, the
Israelis, you guys have seen this this
clown Raza Palavi uh on TV, right? The
crown prince of Iran,
>> right?
>> Oh, yeah. whose wife is carrying on a
very public affair with her personal
trainer, which is an utter humiliation
in Islamic culture.
>> Sure.
>> Totally unacceptable.
He He's got a 14-year-old. They live
here in PTOIC, Maryland. And um the guy
hasn't been in Iran since he was like 16
or 17 years old. They stole everything
they could steal and get it on these
planes and he's just lived fat and happy
in Maryland ever since. And what now?
He's supposed to go back to Iran to
crown himself king like his father did.
Place the crown on his own head like
Napoleon. So, um,
if you are an Iranian millionaire in
Beverly Hills, yeah, he's your guy.
That's where his support comes from.
That's where his support ends.
Literally, nobody in Iran wants that
family, the Palavi family, to uh to take
over leadership. So, who takes over
leadership in the event of a of a coup
or a or a revolution or an uprising or
whatever? Who knows? The Israeli plan is
that the US would install him
and then for our trouble and all the
money that it cost us to, you know, bomb
these guys and bring carrier battle
groups, we would get 49% of Iran's oil.
They would keep 51%.
and presumably everybody would live
happily ever after. That's a fantasy.
That's never going to happen. We tried
that in 1953. We're still paying the
price. It's just not going to happen.
First of all, he wouldn't survive the
walk from the plane to the terminal if
he were even to go back. Secondly, his
own people would murder him because he's
he's a cuck. I mean, let's be honest
here. This is a humiliation, not just
for him, but for all Iranian men,
>> right?
Um,
Iranians I think want democracy.
I'm I'm going to disagree with many of
my friends and say that I I don't
believe that the Ayatollas are popular.
I think that if Iranians could truly
have their choice, they'd throw these
guys out.
But it it is not up to us. It's not up
to the Israelis, nor should it be, to
decide who gets to be the president of
Iran.
you know, is Pierce Morgan, I was on the
Pierce Morgan show recently, and he
said, uh,
uh, are the Iranians are a threat to the
United States? I said, 'Of course not.
He said, 'W wait a minute, what? You
just said the Iranians are not a threat
to the United States. I said, no,
they're not a threat to the United
States. They don't even have a missile
capable of reaching the United States.
But that's not the issue. The issue is,
are they a threat to Israel? And
everybody knows because Benjamin
Netanyahu says it every 15 seconds that
Iran is a an existential threat to
Israel. But guess what? Israel is an
existential threat to Iran.
>> The Iranians aren't killing Israeli
generals. The Iranians aren't killing
Israeli scientists. The Israel The
Iranians aren't wantingly bombing Israel
whenever they feel like it. It's the
Israelis that are the threat to the
Iran. Sounds like Iran can't even
compete with Israeli intelligence. And
>> they know they can't. The the Iranian
intelligence service is one of the
worst, one of the most inept on the
planet
>> because of corruption or
>> it's a in part it's corruption, in part
it's sanctions, in part it's nobody
wants to teach them.
>> You [clears throat] got to learn from
somebody.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Right. So Russia's not heavily
involved in Iran trying to
>> The Russians have robust trade relations
with Iran, but they like to keep it just
there. They're not interested in making
things friendlier.
>> It feels like while Russia's distracted
with Ukraine, Trump is trying to take
advantage to sort of secure this
hemisphere and taking out any Russian
>> allies. Isn't that interesting?
>> Doesn't it seem like Venezuela,
>> you know, I'm of two minds?
Yes. Yes, that's exactly what it seems
like to me. But I'm I'm of two minds
here. Um, you know, of course, we have
the for better, for worse, we have the
Monroe Doctrine. President James Monroe
in his 1823 State of the Union address
said that the United States would oppose
any European involvement in the Western
Hemisphere. That was a slap at the
British, plain and simple.
Nobody even realized he had said it
until seven years later a member of the
House of Representatives quoted it and
called it the Monroe Doctrine.
Even then, nobody paid attention to it
until 1852
when the British said, "Hey, these
islands down here, the Las Malvenas,
we're going to call them the Faullands
and we're going to just take them." And
the Argentines were like, "Well, wait a
minute. The Americans have this thing
called the Monroe Doctrine, and they say
you can't do that." And the British
said, "What are you going to do about
it?" And they took them anyway.
And then in Washington again, 1852,
people said, "Hm,
maybe we should make good on this Monroe
Doctrine thing because we're kind of
looking stupid now." And so we decided
then to take it seriously.
In the 1850s and 1860s, we forged a very
close and abiding relationship with the
government of Venezuela.
We didn't know what oil was yet. It
hadn't been discovered anywhere. We
wouldn't have known what to do with it
anyhow. But they had lots of gold. And
so the British said, "You know what?
This country, Venezuela, it has a lot of
gold, so we're going to take it." And
the British just invaded Venezuela and
took all their gold. So the Venezuelans
came to us. This is like 1868 by by the
time this happened. And they said, "Hey,
you guys have this thing called the
Monroe Doctrine and the British just
invaded us and they're taking all of our
gold. So, what are you going to do about
it? It's time to either put up or shut
up." And um and President Andrew Johnson
said, "They've got a point, right? Well,
we can't attack the British because we
just came out of the Civil War and we
were weak." So, we sued them. We sued
the British on behalf of the
Venezuelans. And we went to what then
was the International Court in Geneva,
Switzerland, and we said, "The British
have no right to this gold. It's
Venezuelan gold. It's our hemisphere
because we said so. And we want the
British out."
And the court said, "All right, our
decision is that the British can keep
90% of the gold and Venezuela can keep
10% of the gold." And we were
high-fiving each other. It's like we won
10% of your gold back.
That was a victory.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. And then as we got a little bolder
and stronger, Teddy Roosevelt became
president. And in 1905, he told the
Brits, "You out of Venezuela."
And they finally bugged out. And the
Venezuelans have mined their own gold
ever since. But anyway,
>> until until recently.
>> Until recently. So it was only in 1905
that the Monroe Doctrine really became
an actual thing. But it was because
there was a multi-olar world, right? You
had the Tsarist Empire, you had the
British Empire, you had the French
Empire. The US was feeling like maybe
stretching our legs a little bit around
the world. It was genuinely a multipolar
world. So we decided it's easiest to
protect the Western Hemisphere. So,
we're just going to redeclare this
Monroe Doctrine and the Western
Hemisphere is ours. Well, we were the
bad guys in most of those cases. We just
forcibly took the Panama Canal or took
Panama and then cut the canal. Um, we
overthrew countless Latin American
governments, multiple governments in the
Dominican Republic in in uh Guatemala.
You guys know the the Arben story? Why
we why we overthrew Arbenz? Do you know
that story?
>> I was just reading about it from David
Talbot. I was reading that book.
>> Oh, David Talbot is absolutely
brilliant. Um, do you know about the
United Fruit Company?
>> A little bit. I would love for you to
explain it though. It's it's a crazy
story.
>> So, in the late 19th century, this rich
industrialist from Boston decided that
he's going to build a a train system
from Guatemala City to the um coast.
Right. So he he's going to have a
monopoly on transport and anything that
needs to be exported, it's going to have
to go on his train. So he just buys this
little narrow strip just wide enough for
a train from Guatemala City to the coast
and hires hundreds of workers to lay the
track. Every day these workers who he's
paying you know pennies an hour. Every
day these workers take a lunch break and
they just go to the edge of the jungle
and they pull these fruits off the
trees.
And he says, "What are these fruits that
that these workers are are eating every
day." And he's told that they're called
bananas. He had never heard of b of a
banana before. He'd never seen a banana.
They were unknown to Americans. So he
tasted one and it was delicious. So he
decided,
I'm going to buy all the land on the two
sides of the train tracks and I'm going
to put the bananas on the train and ship
the bananas to the United States. That
was the start of what became known as
the United Fruit Company, which today is
called Chaita Banana. So it went through
several different ownerships
and in 1953
the government of general or government
sorry of president uh uh Hakobo Arbenz
said you know we've been exporting these
bananas for half a century. We're not
making anything on them. There are
bananas.
I'm going to nationalize the the banana
crop and the national fruit company's
going to have to lump it.
Well, it turned out that three members
of the board of directors of the United
Fruit Company were John Foster Dulles,
the secretary of state, Alan Dulles, the
director of the CIA,
and President Eisenhower's secretar's
brother.
And so they overthrew our Benbs. They
installed a military dictatorship that
brutalized the Guatemalan people for the
next half a century
and Chaita Banana still owns the
bananas.
>> Can we talk about the Dulles brothers
for a moment?
>> Yeah. Monsters, both of them.
>> Were Were they still idolized when you
entered the CIA? Like was John Foster
Doulles and especially Allan Doulles? I
heard that Allen had made a bust of his
head that you'd see when you'd walk into
the CIA headquarters.
>> Yeah, that's true. Was he still spoke of
just very highly?
>> No, I actually asked that when I when I
first started working at the CI. I asked
about him and I asked about uh James
Angleton. Like I was really curious what
people thought about those guys.
Dulles was just kind of forgotten. It
was so long ago, right? He he ended his
tenure 19 well January of 1961. Um
everybody's dead and gone from those
days.
and Angleton. I did meet a couple of
oldtimers who crossed paths with
Angleton and they said that everybody
feared Angleton.
You know, they respected Dulles because,
you know, we were kicking asses and
taking names all around the world, which
was a cool thing from 1952 to 1960 for a
lot of people. um you know we were
confronting the Soviets and and the the
British Empire had been destroyed
because World War II was so expensive
and they couldn't maintain India and it
broke into Pakistan and then later uh
Bangladesh and all of a sudden we were
the the big guys on the block. Um but
Angleton people were genuinely afraid
of. My first boss at the agency told me
that he had actually started at the
agency um in the what was called the
graduate fellowship program. So they
would take, you know, high-erforming
grad students, give them a secret
security clearance, not a top secret,
and then they would, you know, make
copies and get coffee and, you know, go
to briefings and whatever. So he
started, he ended up being a senior
intelligence service level four
assistant secretary of defense when he
finally retired. But he said when he
was, you know, 22, 23 years old, uh, he
got his first grad fellowship and it was
in Angleton's office. I said, "No way."
He said, "Seriously, I worked for James
Angleton." Dang.
>> And he said on his first day, the
secretary
gave him a tour of the office. It was
the counter intelligence center.
And um he said, "When you first walked
in, there was this wall of file folders.
When when I first got started, we
weren't computerized yet. I I still
can't believe I'm that old already, but
we had IBM Select Electric 3 typewriters
on our desks and these giant boxes with
green little green screens called Delta
Datas." And we we were just entering the
computer age. So it was all paper when
he started. And um he said that the
secretary told him um every once in a
while you may find yourself alone in the
office. Whatever you do, don't look in
those files. And I laughed when he said
it. He goes, I know, I know. So what's
the first thing I do? He said, I ran to
the files as soon as like everybody's
out at some going away party or
whatever. I ran to the files. He said,
every single one of those files was on
an American citizen. No way. Oh my gosh.
>> Every one of them.
>> And Angleton was supposed to be on the
the European theater, wasn't it? I
thought I forget where Angleton exactly
was, but I thought he was the director
of European affairs for the CIA.
>> Almost his whole career was spent on
counter intelligence. But just to make
it worse, he was Kim Phily's best man.
>> Yes.
>> And Kim Philby was his best man. And you
know, Angleton was obsessed with moles.
He he thought everybody at the CIA was
potentially a Soviet mole. And in fact,
it was Philby that was the mole. His
best friend.
>> Yeah. Philby was a famous spy for the
Soviets.
>> Angleton never got over that. Philby was
the number two or number three in MI6,
the British Intelligence Service. He had
been recruited by the KGB when he was in
college and he was directed to join MI6.
He didn't realize he's going to end up
being the deputy director of MI6. So
when word leaked out that he was one of
the the three Meredith
I forget I forget the other guy's name.
There was a fourth who who came clean
later like in the 80s. But anyway, when
people started pointing the finger and
saying the mole has to be Philby and
then others were like it's not possible
for the somebody that senior, you know,
who meets with the queen for him to be
the mole. But there was enough
circumstantial evidence that they
removed him from his position and they
sent him to Beirut
and then
another mole tipped off the KGB that the
Brits were going to arrest him. He went
to the British ambassador's Christmas
party in Beirut at the at the
ambassador's residence. He got a message
triggering a meeting with his handler.
And the only reason to trigger an
emergency meeting was, "You've been
outed. you've got to run. He excused
himself from dinner to go to the
bathroom, climbed out the window of the
bathroom, and escaped to the Soviet
embassy. And then they smuggled him back
to Moscow. Like six days later, he
appeared at a press conference in Moscow
and said, "Ha, I was the mole the whole
time, suckers."
>> Wow. He used to lecture
at the KGB training center to all the
the brand new KGB officers. Unlike
really any other mole or defector,
you know, one of the dirty little
secrets of espionage is let's say I I
recruit you as a penetration of a
foreign intelligence service. you're
you're a mole and I tell you you're so
great and I'm giving you a million
dollars and I tell you that the
president himself sends his best regards
which I'm making up, you know, or we've
we've issued you a medal. I can't show
it to you because it's classified and we
have to keep it in a safe at
headquarters, but you just got the
highest medal that the CIA you know, you
do that kind of thing all the time.
>> Normal. But if you need to come back to
the CIA because you've been outed and
your country's going to kill you, you
can't just walk the halls of the CIA
like you own the place.
Deep down, we consider you to be a
traitor. We're glad that you were a
traitor for us, but you're still a
traitor.
>> Well, Philby, you know, they gave they
gave him a staff position, a teaching
position. We consider the the moles that
we have to be traders because
>> they're tradering for against our
enemies, but the fact that they're
willing to be a traitor is less ideal.
>> Yeah. Because 95% of them are doing it
for the money,
>> right?
>> And if they'll if they'll
>> But isn't everybody doing it for the
money? I mean, [laughter]
>> well, if they commit treason against
their own country, why wouldn't they
commit treason against us?
>> Right. Sure.
>> So, we just, you know, we thank mafia
rules. We we set them up in a house and
with a business and, you know, don't
worry about anything. They they have
enough money for the rest of their
lives. But yeah, you're not just going
to have a staff badge and just drive
into the CIA compound and take your
parking space.
>> Got it.
>> But in Russia,
>> they did with Philby. He was the real
deal from the beginning.
>> Amazing.
>> You know, people said that I I worked
for a guy. I didn't work for him. He was
the head of research for an office that
I was working in. So, he was sort of
like a a dotted line on the org chart.
Um, and he was an old-timer. And he said
that when he first got hired as a junior
analyst and he would be walking down the
halls and he would see uh uh Angleton,
he would turn around and go the other
way. He said Angleton kind of went kooky
after a while. when when he first
learned that it was Philby that was the
mole the whole time, he kind of lost his
mind and never got it back.
>> It would really break your reality,
>> I think, to have your best friend be the
mole for that many years.
>> And and not only is he your best friend,
>> he's the godfather to your child.
We have a word for it in Greek and the
Italians do too. We we say kumbi and
they say kari in Italian. There's no
English word for it really, but it's
like you're you're related. I mean, it's
like
>> a brother-in-law, you know, you're part
of the family and that's the trader.
You've been looking for traders all over
the agency all these years, decades, and
that's the trader. It's the guy that
you've been sharing the information
about your hunt for traders with. That's
the trader.
>> I think that would drive any man a
little bit. Mhm.
>> Uh it would dishevel you to a point
where it'd be hard to ever get your feet
underneath you.
>> Yeah. And you know that people are
saying behind your back, "What kind of
judgment does this guy?"
>> Totally. Everything calls into question.
>> But he knew he had been doing some
filthy stuff. Angleton didn't. I think
on his deathbed, he said like, "I'll see
the I'll see my boys back in hell."
>> Yeah,
>> he knew.
>> He did.
>> And he was a bad guy.
>> Yeah.
>> Angleton was a bad guy.
>> Well, back if we if we roll back the
clock a little bit more, it seems to me
that the CIA was actually more on the
side of sort of Nazi money. Oh yeah,
FBI. It was the CIA. It was the
predecessor of the CIA that brought all
these Nazi scientists in with Operation
Paperclip.
>> And the FBI was really the ones that was
like, "No, we don't want the Nazi money
in."
>> Yeah.
>> But the CIA was already looking forward
to when the Soviets were going to be in
power,
>> which is exactly why all those Nazis
gave themselves up to the Americans.
They didn't trust the British. They were
petrified of the Russians, but they
calculated correctly that the US would
lay out the red carpet.
>> Interesting. Yeah.
>> Yeah. There was this whole process of
denazification and a lot of the wealthy
uh Germans. It was very you had to get a
couple of letters from Jewish people
that gave you, you know, that you're my
friend. But it it was basically a
formality essentially where you just
paid enough money and you were
denazified. And once you got that sort
of letter, America was like, you're
you're good. Come on in.
>> Verer von Braun is buried right here in
in Alexandria, Virginia. The guy was at
NASA for all those years.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. and designing rockets to shoot
against us just before that.
>> Wildly Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> Father of the V2.
>> Well, the country makes mistakes and
then it has to try to fix them. And
speaking of that, I think Trump probably
owes you a pardon. Is there any word on
whether or not Trump's even considering
giving you a pardon?
>> I've applied formally.
I have been very very fortunate to get a
letter of support um signed by some of
his closest friends
Tucker Carlson, Dr. Phil, uh Judge
Dalitano,
a couple of um
couple of leaders from the Make America
Great Again Foundation,
major campaign donors. Um,
I know that the letter got to the US
pardon attorney and
the pardon attorney made a comment
recently that not a day goes by that at
least two people don't call him, write
him or email him asking him to pardon
me. So,
I'm hoping for the best.
>> I think we're all rooting for it at this
point.
>> Appreciate it.
>> 100%. And did you get any what did you
feel when I think Julian Assange reached
a deal?
>> Yeah. So,
you know, God bless Donald Trump for
doing that.
>> At least he made some motion, right?
>> No, it wasn't Trump, was it?
>> No, that was uh
>> that was Biden.
>> That was Biden. Yeah, that was before
>> Trump was going to do it. Trump said
publicly that he would do it. He did
pardon Ross Olrich though,
>> which was an awesome thing to do.
>> You know, just before that pardon came
down or whatever it was, commutation or
pardon, I can't recall. Either way, I
met with Ross's mom and sister, they
make they made such a compelling
argument. I I asked them to be on my
podcast and then boom, the pardon came
through. Yeah. And I was like, "Wow, he
deserved a pardon."
>> Yeah.
>> That poor guy was seriously wronged.
>> I mean, okay, even if he did even if
what he did was illegal.
>> So, what do other people who do the same
thing get? 5 years
>> and you're out in uh in four.
>> Mhm.
>> Come on.
>> Yeah. He was still sitting there 10
years later. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's not cool.
>> No, that's not cool.
You know, I I say this all the time, and
I'm at the risk of repeating myself, I'm
going to say it again. The United States
has 5% of the world's population, right?
We have 25% of the world's prison
population. Over the last 20 years,
Congress has created 50 new crimes, not
laws, 50 new crimes every single year.
meaning something that you could do a
year ago that nobody gave a [__] about
today is a felony. I I wrote I've
written in the past about a couple of
egregious cases. These these were during
the Obama administration.
>> There was a woman um who worked for uh
Noah, the National Oceanic and
Atmospheric Administration, the weather
people. Yep.
>> So she worked in Noah's Honolulu office,
which is kind of a big Noah site. and
she was a GS12. Honolulu is an expensive
place to live. You can't live on a GS12
salary. So, she and a partner uh bought
a boat and they would take tourists out
on the boat and go whale watching. So,
they're out whale watching one day and
they come across a pod of orcas feeding
on a seal, right? They're just tearing
at the seal carcass. Everybody goes to
the side of the boat. They're taking
pictures, taking video.
Somebody goes
at the whale.
Okay. Like to make sure the whale stays.
>> Look at me taking a photo.
>> Yeah. I'm taking a picture.
>> Couple of weeks later,
FBI open the door. She opens the door. I
said, "FBI,
we're doing a uh an investigation. You
have this uh boat. You take tourists
out." She said, "Yeah." Did you take
tourists out two weeks ago? Yes.
Did you see a whale? Yeah, we saw whales
eating a seal.
Did you whistle at the whale? She said,
"No." Somebody did, I think, but I
didn't.
She said, "But you know what? I
videotape every trip and then I sell the
DVDs to the to the tourists." They took
that DVD. They came back with a search
warrant, took all of her DVDs and her
laptop and her cell phone, and they
ended up charging her with a felony
count of interfering with the feeding of
a wild animal, which is a violation of
the Endangered Species Act.
She fought this thing for five years
and just to make it go away, she took a
a plea to a misdemeanor count of
interfering with the feeding of a wild
animal. Well, she lost her job at Noah.
Her boat was repossessed. She lost her
condo. She lost her pension. Her friend,
her partner never spoke to her again.
Fighting those battles is not cheap.
>> No, I spent I spent $1.15 million.
I'm still paying.
>> And you're not getting your benefits.
>> No, they took my pension off of it.
>> So, this kind of thing happens all the
time. There was a fisherman in Alabama.
Not Yeah, in Alabama. And um he was out
hunting. He was out fishing for halibet,
right? Who doesn't love halibet? Not
halibet. Forgive me. Hamore. What?
What's hammud in English? It's um
grouper.
>> Grouper,
>> right? Everybody loves grouper. It's
like the state fish of Florida, right?
It's everywhere.
>> Well, there's a law that the grouper has
to be 12 in. You have to throw it back
in.
>> So, these fish and wildlife guys come up
to his boat. They've got the little red
light spinning around. They want to come
on the boat, which they are perfectly
welcome to do. They get on the boat.
They pull out the tape measure up. One
of the fish is 11 in and it's still
flopping around. He said, "No problem.
I'll just throw it back in." No, no, no.
You already caught it. You're under
arrest.
They charged him. This is a felony. They
charged him with a felony because the
grouper was 11 in instead of 12 in. He
lost everything. He lost his boat. He
lost his business. He lost his money. He
lost everything. He lost his fishing
license. Everything.
Well, are you and I better off because
they arrested this guy for having a fish
that was one inch too small? Are we
better off because the Noah woman uh was
convicted of whistling at the whale? Is
society better?
>> Yeah. What's going on here? Why is this
abuse of power happening? Is it lack of
incentives?
>> That's easy. No, I can tell you
because this is how people get promoted.
>> Oh, right.
>> The FBI is not going to get promoted by
not arresting you. like I went to the
house, but uh he had a plausible excuse.
I didn't arrest him.
>> But are you gonna get promoted for
getting a guy on 11 in fish over 12 in?
It doesn't m It's not like you got to
get the biggest bust. It's just getting
the criminals.
>> Your cases have resulted in 100% guilty
verdicts.
>> Oh my gosh. It's a percentbased
>> because listen, I I can tell you from
firsthand
experience, every assistant US attorney
sees himself or herself eventually
running for Congress, running for
governor, being the US attorney, being
in some A-list law for law firm's corner
office, making $6 million a year,
>> climbing the ranks,
>> and they're going to do it on your back
>> through kingdom building.
>> That's right. That's exactly what it is.
It's kingdom building. Yes.
>> It
>> It's bloated. It feels like every
organism needs to have a defense system.
Like we have our we have our immune
system, but once the immune system
becomes too big, it's cancerous. It
kills you.
>> Very you're you're exactly right.
>> I heard a statistic that the FBI has
250,000
paid civilian informants throughout the
country. I
>> I don't know if that's real, but that's
a that's a report I saw that allegedly
was from the FBI itself. You know, there
are famous now declassified reports of
um the FBI infiltrating uh antivietnam
war protest groups to the point where,
you know, six guys would show up for one
of these meetings and all six of them
were FBI agents, not knowing that the
all the others were FBI agents and
they're all ratting each other out in
their reports.
>> I mean, does every country have this
problem? Does China have the same
problem?
>> China may.
>> China might. It's possible.
>> Who do you think I if anyone has moles
in the US, which country would you guess
is doing the best job right now?
>> China, Israel, Russia are the three big
ones. Yes.
>> Okay. What are they here for? Secrets,
education,
>> almost entirely defense secrets. The
Russians have that longer term view
again. You know, they have this thing
called the illegals program, also called
the sleeper program, where
they'll take you at the age of 12,
and they'll send you to this camp and
you're going to watch American TV shows
and American movies and speak learn to
speak American accented English so that
nobody can tell that you're Russian.
And what they do, it's harder today, but
what they used to do is they'll find in
the social security records, um,
somebody born the same year as you, but
who died as an infant,
and then they'll apply for a social
security card in that name, which is now
your new name. And with a social
security card, you get everything. You
get a driver's license, you get a you
get a passport, you get a, you know,
>> utilities turned on, and you come here
with your fake US P or now it's actually
a real US passport because you've
applied for it uh in that name and you
get a job as you know well in in the
Netflix show the Americans they were
travel agents or in my neighborhood here
in Arlington this woman was a freaking
special ed teacher and here she's a KGB
sleeper agent the whole time and you
just lead this normal life until you're
activated and And you know, you may go
20 years without being activated, but
once you're activated, you do as you're
told, and then you go back into your
deep cover again. And the activation may
be
that they want you to shoot somebody in
the head. Or they want you to put on
these shoes that they brought you cuz
they have this special adhesive on the
on the soles and they want you to walk
around outside a nuclear plant to see
how much um radiation is leaking or walk
around outside this factory because we
think it's a nuclear missile factory and
the Americans say it's a you know
bicycle factory and then you just go
back into your your cover life again.
>> It's pretty sophisticated.
Who's that?
>> We don't do that.
>> Do you think that there are moles in our
graduate programs right now? Because
>> absolutely. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Mostly Chinese.
>> Mostly Chinese. What What sorts of
things will they be studying?
>> The hard sciences.
>> Oh, that kind of makes sense,
>> you know. But that's a that's a
two-edged sword
because the Chinese send them here to
get PhDs in, you know, astrophysics or
whatever or organic chemistry.
And then while they're here, we're like,
they're probably Chinese moles. We
should flip them,
>> right? We sell them
>> and then we try to flip them and send
them back to China to then report to us.
>> How do you flip a a mole?
>> It's hard.
>> You get them dating an American girl.
Sure. That might scare him away.
Actually,
>> yeah. You know, I was just teaching a
class a couple of days ago and I was
using this wonderful, wonderful book
called Fair Play that um a former CIA
officer named Olsen wrote. He used to be
the director of the counter intelligence
center. This book is fantastic. And what
he does is he he offers up like a
hundred different scenarios that many of
us in operations, you know, encountered
on a day-to-day basis. And then he'll
ask people's opinions, professors,
lawyers, grad students, former CIA,
former FBI,
and there are disagreements across the
board, like what do you do? So, one of
the questions was
there's a uh there's a Russian PhD
candidate in the United States. The FBI
believes that he's a sleeper agent. And
so
a CIA case officer is assigned to just
accidentally bump into him at the tennis
club where he goes. So she goes to the
tennis club. She sees him practicing his
serve. She says, "Wow, you know, you
have a really great serve." He takes a
liking to her. She invites him for a
drink in the bar. They have a drink.
They start dating. It's clear to her
that his interest is romantic and she's
holding him off.
So,
she assesses that he is weak personally.
He's very lonely.
Um, he may have a drinking problem,
but he would be very valuable to us as
as a double as a double agent to double
him back against the Russians. and she
tells her boss, "I'm willing to have sex
with him.
Do you allow her to?"
And everybody was like, "Yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes." And then Olsson writes
the actual right answer, which is
absolutely not.
>> Right.
>> You don't let her have sex with him.
>> No.
I mean, you got to draw the line
somewhere, right?
>> Right. Right.
That's incredible. Do do you have to
draw the line somewhere? I I think in a
real fight rules kind of go out the
window.
>> Sometimes sometimes I worked with a
woman who had been a case officer in
Latin America and she recruited this guy
and immediately started sleeping with
him and then she came clean to her boss
and he's like, "You're out.
>> Out."
>> So for a while they switched her from
ops to analysis which is a real smack
across the face. She married the guy and
then after the investigation was done,
they threw her out.
>> You know, this is pretty common though.
I mean, I know America did this to the
British when we were breaking away from
them. I mean, we needed the cotton gin
and water mills and trains and I mean,
we we had they had the British had
technology that we wanted and we would
also send moles over to England to try
and steal the plants, work at the
factory, work at whatever was going on
to bring that industry back to America.
So this is not something that's like
specific to any nation. It's Sun Sue,
art of war. I mean, it's if your
opponent's more powerful, this is the
way to go. Get stuff from them.
>> Espionage is specifically mentioned in
the Bible on multiple occasions,
>> right?
>> Yeah. It's been around a long time.
Well, they say it's the second oldest
profession.
[laughter]
>> They do. I mean, they've always said
that [clears throat]
>> it's a supererset of the oldest
profession,
>> basically. Yeah.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> Last time we chatted with you, you said
that there was actually a ground game
going on in Africa. You said that there
were US Do you have
>> We're losing.
>> What's going on?
>> The Chinese are just throwing money at
everybody.
>> Against us or
>> No, no, no, no, not against us. They
don't even need to.
>> Oh,
>> like that Onion uh headline said, the
Chinese are perfectly happy to sit back
and watch us destroy ourselves and we're
burning.
>> Yeah. So a congalles diplomat said to me
one time, you know, you promise us
democracy, the Chinese promise us food.
Which one are they going to take? So
you know, the Chinese have this belt and
road initiative. It's been going on for
decades already. It was a big deal when
I was in Pakistan 20 24 years ago.
um
they spend
so little on defense relative to their
population and compared to what we spend
that they're just swimming in money.
Their economy is robust. They've got
some real estate problems now. But their
economy is generally robust, especially
manufacturing, swimming in money. And so
they just go to every country in Africa
and say, "What do you need? You need
roads?" Done. You need a port. you need
an airport, you need hospitals, you need
schools, not a problem. Just sign this
99-year lease on your rare earth metals.
And they say, "Fine." And then the
Chinese build all this stuff. The
Chinese are all over Africa and now
making inroads into South America
because they can provide whatever these
countries want. And then we tell the
same countries,
"We've got some old F-16s
that are sitting in mothballs over here.
We're going to give you two of them."
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. What do you think of that?
[laughter]
>> And they're like, "Come on. The Chinese
are already They beat you to it."
>> Yeah. They're building libraries and
beautiful things.
>> Exactly. Do you have an opinion on I I
saw this thing recently around how the
population of China may not be as large
as they say it is just by taking sheer
statistics of birth rates that should
have happened when we knew the
population 50 years ago
>> and even you can sometimes measure the
population of a country by salt
consumption.
>> Oh, that's interesting. I heard that.
>> It [clears throat] doesn't matter how
rich or poor you are. Every human needs
pretty much the same amount of
electrolytes. And so you can actually
track electrolyte traffic and proxy
populations. Interesting.
>> And basically it seems like China might
only have it might be about the size of
the US. Maybe 300 maybe 500 million
people.
>> What?
>> Yeah. Not the one point whatever they
say they have.
>> I hadn't heard that. I I did hear that
early last year India officially passed
China.
>> Um I hadn't heard that. They have a
serious real estate problem
>> with hundreds of thousands of units just
sitting completely empty.
>> Yeah. Those people have to be living
somewhere if they exist and they don't
appear to be living anywhere. So
>> yeah, I think it was something like
every woman needed to have five kids on
average for the last 50 years for the
growth rate to be it was some it was
some ridiculous number and they've had
the one one child policy that we all
know about. And so they're just like
statistically there cannot be over a
billion people in China. It's not
possible. You know the Russian um the
Russian rate of population growth is so
low. There was an editorial about this
not too long ago. They said that um in I
think it's a hundred years there won't
be any Russians.
>> They're just going to die out. Now, of
course, that's not going to happen
because they'll they'll institute
incentives for people to have more
children. Immigration will turn people
into Russians.
But, I mean, you have to think, right?
>> I mean, Elon has been talking about this
a lot. I mean I do it sort of seems like
our global population might be on the
decline uh just in terms of you know you
need 2.1 ch babies per family to two to
replace you and 0.1 for all the
accidents and just things that happen
and growth rates are now abysmally below
too in many western nations and that
only you know you do the math and go
three generations out and the population
is a quarter of what it was and I think
it's you know it's hard to reverse
demographics are one of those things
where you kind of see a hundredyear
train wreck and once that year is done
and all the babies have been born in
2025. You can't make more babies out of
2025. And so it does seem like
>> I think that's sort of lending sort of
the whole macro visual of the whole
world right now is everybody's
regionalizing again. It's sort of like
everyone's sort of going after their own
resources because we're contracting.
Yeah.
>> And I've so bloiated I got off track.
First of all, that is an outstanding
op-ed right there.
>> Oh, cool.
>> I think a a lot of papers would run
that. That's important.
>> We were talking about spheres of
influence. I I started talking about the
Monroe Doctrine, but I think that
snatching Maduro was kind of a signal to
the Chinese and the Russians that
Venezuela's ours. We'll concede that
Taiwan is yours and Ukraine is yours.
>> Absolutely.
>> There it is. Absolutely a signal.
Everyone's regionalizing. Everyone's
spread to thin.
>> That's what made me think of it.
>> Yeah. Populations are declining and so
the the wagons are circling now. It's a
big circle because the world's huge from
regional region to region, but it the
incentives are there to contract
>> and we're just watching. It's it's not
usually peaceful when that happens. It's
because economies go down things, you
know, it's very problematic to shrink in
size versus growth is always very
helpful. It covers over a multitude of
issues. And just last week there was a
piece in the post that um population
growth continues in the United States
but at the lowest level in more than a
decade because we've so clamped down on
immigration.
>> Yeah. And so you can influx artificially
through immigration but you know that
has its own that's not
>> black and white. There's a lot of nuance
there.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> What's up for grabs there in these
fears? Because you're saying Russia,
China, it's a tripolar world I guess.
Yeah. Maybe China and Russia would have
more connection to each other. Or is or
will Russia just stay independent of
China regardless?
>> You know, I think that the Russians are
weaker and weaker as time passes.
>> Well, they're losing a lot of guys every
week.
>> A lot. Yeah. And I think that the that
the real rivalry now is going to be
simply us and the Chinese. I I really
believe that.
>> And where do the OPEC producers fall?
>> You know, isn't that funny? OPEC used to
be so important. They were a part of
every conversation. And now it's like
nobody really cares anymore. When I was
a kid, I I teach this in my history of
terrorism course. One of the most
fascinating characters to me in in
contemporary history is Carlos the
Jackal. This guy was a terrorist
Superman. You know, people are were so
afraid of Osama bin Laden. You didn't
know Carlos the Jackal.
>> Where was he from? I don't know Carlos
the Jackal.
>> Oh, Ilitch Ramirez Sanchez. He was the
most important terrorist in the world in
the 1970s and 1980s.
>> Okay.
>> He was Venezuelan.
>> Got it.
>> But he was an international man of
mystery. Right. The Venezuelans would
have been perfectly happy to arrest him.
>> The evil James Bond.
>> Yeah. He he was he was James Bond's
nemesis. In the 1970s, 1975 I guess it
was, all the OPEC nations had an OPEC
ministerial meeting. All the ministers
of oil from every OPEC nation. They met
in Vienna and Carlos and his and his
crew kidnapped all of them at once.
[laughter]
All of them. And he said, "I want a
billion dollars. I'm going to start
shooting them every hour."
>> Whoa.
>> And they paid.
>> Yeah,
>> they paid.
>> Incredible.
>> That's incredible.
>> Wow.
>> Like, who has the guts?
Who has the brain that can even conceive
of an operation like we should kidnap
the oil ministers? Every one of them.
>> All of them.
>> Yeah. And then he did it.
>> That would be like getting all the tech
CEOs right now all at once.
>> All at once. You you go to Davos, you
just grab everybody,
>> right?
>> And just hold them.
>> Yeah. What did you think of uh Davos the
WF meeting that they had? Do you have
any any cliff notes?
>> You know,
somebody to whom I used to be very close
uh
goes to Davos and Shangrila and you know
all of these things.
She told me that
all they ever talk about is arms deals.
That's really all it comes down to. The
heads of state make these semi-important
speeches that the media carry, but all
the actual private chatter, all the
private conversations, they're all about
arms deals. That's all that ever happens
at those places.
You know, it's not like
the Jewish bankers from the city of
London are secretly arriving to plot out
the global economy. No. No. They're
like, "Listen, these F-35s, we want
these
Yeah, that kind of thing. And I think
that's really what happened at Davos. We
got Carney speech and Trump made a
speech and everybody makes a speech, but
I don't think that's really what what
was accomplished.
What how did you feel after Venezuela
when they captured Maduro and Trump was
standing on the stage and then I I
forget it was one of the generals that
stepped up and he basically looked at
the camera and said, "We've been
practicing. We can do this anytime,
anywhere." whenever we want.
>> That's absolutely true.
>> He We're sort of trying to resolidify
ourselves as the bullies, aren't we?
>> Because violence is our business, I
guess.
>> Yeah. You know, I'm I'm a little
embarrassed to say it, but this is this
is the country we've given ourselves. We
We made a national conscious decision
that this was who we were going to be.
>> Yeah. I've heard it said that populist
presidents are summoned. They're not the
people summon the populist president.
>> I think that's a great way to look at
it.
>> Yeah. That's it's not that he's doing
anything that is he's the people want
this. There's this reason
>> Donald Trump didn't come down from the
sky.
>> No,
>> we chose him.
>> That's right.
>> Mhm. And this is another thing. Oh man,
we were just making friends of mine and
I last night at dinner, we were making
fun of this hless woman from
Indianapolis. As a matter of fact, she
and her husband had this successful
steakhouse, right? and he came here 35
years ago without papers. He's illegal
this whole time, but he married this
woman, never filed his paperwork. They
opened this restaurant. It's very
successful. They have plenty of money.
Trump is elected. They grab him, send
him to an ice prison, send him back to
Mexico. And she voted for Trump. And
she's crying on the local news and she
said he said he was only gonna take the
bad ombres. Okay. The point I want to
make is Donald Trump at every step of
the way has told us exactly what he
intended to do. And the Democrats always
underestimate him. He's far brighter
than the Democrats think he is. And he's
not like pulling a fast one than
anybody. He tells us exactly what he
intends to do
>> and then we're shocked when he does it.
I think that's what the populace was so
surprised about him in is just how
honest he was.
>> Yeah.
>> Because I think that the narrative for
20 years has been that, you know,
politicians smile at you and say things
and then they do arms deals behind you.
you know, they go to Davos and they talk
about peace and then they go do arms
deals and eventually if you just think
that's going on and then you get a guy,
you know, whether you like his message
or not, but he says what he's going to
do and he does that and he seems honest,
>> it's hard to it's it's appealing in that
way at least regardless of the message
is this is a guy who's not lying at
least and that some something about that
feels like I have agency now because I
can, you know, I'm not being fooled. I
think you've hit it on the head. And you
know, 2028 is right around the corner.
And I don't think that the Democrats
have been able to do anything to
discredit populism,
>> right?
>> They just haven't.
>> They seem more disorganized.
>> Oh, I think they're in chaos.
>> Does it seem It seems like Gavin is
probably going to be their best bet
upcoming election. Okay.
>> But, you know, coming from a state like
California, he's going to be very easy
to attack. Totally.
>> Yeah. I go to I go to California a lot
and I never get over the shock of $55 a
gallon gasoline.
I won't do it.
I can't imagine living there. And taxes
are so insanely high.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's, you know, you have
all the tech guys moving from California
to Texas.
>> And Texas is a free state, so there's no
state income tax. And California is
what, 13%. So that's outrageous.
>> You can move and you get a 13% raise
just from moving. I mean some for some a
lot of people that's free housing.
>> Yeah,
>> that's pretty appealing depending how
much money you make. That's I mean you
can make any amount of money and free
13% is pretty interesting.
>> But he started texting in all caps and
he uses hands a lot now when he talks. I
don't know if you've seen Gavin in
recent interview.
>> Oh no.
>> He just moves his hands. It's like he's
trying to become a Trump. Listen,
anybody I'll tell you the reason why I
why why I hate Gavin Newsome and to the
point where I would never vote for him.
You know, he was this golden boy for a
long time. He was a he was a member of
the city council of San Francisco and
then he became the chairman of city
council. Then he was mayor of San
Francisco and then he was lieutenant
governor and then he was governor. Well,
when he was running for governor, he's
running for lieutenant governor.
um [clears throat] he asked his best
friend who was his campaign manager to
stand in for him because there were so
many campaign events. You know, it's a
big state, a lot of people. You can't
you can't go to every single campaign
event. So, his best friend, who was his
chief of staff and campaign manager, is
going and representing him. All the
while, Newsome's banging the guy's wife,
>> right?
>> And then they got caught and he's like,
"Ah, sorry. I apologize to the people of
California. People of California,
apologize to your best friend. You've
betrayed a friendship. You can't get
past something like that.
>> If he thinks that little of his best
friend and is willing is willing to to
betray that kind of a friendship, what's
he going to do to you and me?
>> What's he going to do to the country?
Listen, if his own wife can't trust him,
well, how's the country supposed to
trust him? I don't trust him.
>> That's a hard one to overcome when
somebody says that on a stage about you
over and over and over.
>> Exactly.
>> If you had to predict who will be the
two candidates in the next presidential
election, who who do you think they're
aiming for?
>> A lot of my friends disagree with me. I
think Newsome for the Democrats. I think
he's going to be just flush with money.
And
you know this Democratic
policy of superdelegates, the fix is in
from the beginning. Whoever the the
cigar smoking backroom bosses at the DNC
decide is going to be the nominee,
that's going to be the nominee. The
Republicans don't have superdelegates.
Almost all of my friends think it's
going to be JD Vance. And I don't. I
think it's going to be Marco Rubio.
>> Yeah,
>> JD Vance is very young. It's deceiving
actually. He's got the gray beard, but
he's he's very young.
>> He's got
>> he's like 41.
>> Yeah. Two.
>> He's got 35 years that he could still be
running for president. Rubio's already
run.
>> He's been a senator. He's been Secretary
of State. Now he's the national security
adviser. On top of that, he's got
Florida. And after they took over
Venezuela and he was standing up there
with the generals and the president and
they asked him about Cuba, he asked
Marco to step up. Marco, why don't you
talk about this?
>> That's right.
>> It looks like Trump is really favoring
Marco right now as well.
>> I think so, too.
>> Yeah.
>> I think Trump genuinely likes JD Vance
>> for sure.
>> And I think JD Vance genuinely wants to
be schooled in Trump populism,
but I think Rubio's a better politician.
Remember JD Vance? He was a senator for
two years.
>> And didn't we [__] about Obama? Because
all he ever had was that he was a
senator for four years or Yeah. four
years or two years. 06 to08. Two years.
We bitched about him because he was
unqualified to be president. Well, JD
Vance has been vice president now for
four years, but or it'll be for four
years, but he was just a senator for two
years. I think he's just too young.
>> Makes sense. Yeah. And you hold him back
for later. He he can go for a different
election.
>> I think he has a very bright future. I
really do. Tell you the truth, I think
his wife is actually
>> at least as qualified as he is.
>> I don't I don't know much about his
wife.
>> Yeah. Usha, she's very very smart. Very
smart.
>> Top universities, made millions in
investment banking.
>> What do you think's happening with um
what do you think Trump's going to do
around Alex Prey and all the ICE things
going on? Just this afternoon, um DOJ
announced, um a special investigation
special investigation into
>> human I'm sorry, into civil rights
violations.
>> Oh,
>> civil rights violation at the federal
level is akin to a murder charge.
>> Whoa. They just did that this afternoon.
>> Yeah. 3 four hours ago.
>> Oh, man. We were setting up. I didn't
see that.
>> Yeah. So,
>> okay. So, that's a that's a positive
response.
>> Yeah. So many Republican, especially
senators, pushed back saying, "Okay,
we've crossed a line here. You got to do
something." Um, the White House leaked
yesterday that the two guys who fired
the shots had been suspended on
Saturday. They just never announced it.
>> And then this afternoon, they said
they've they've asked a prosecutor to
look into it.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Good.
>> That's great. That is good.
>> Yeah. I think it's I think that it's
hard to see what's going on internally
and you know it just seems like a little
bit of an abuse of power. Yeah.
>> And how do you rein that in? And how do
you if you don't does that mean you just
you
>> you're okay with it
>> when it feels like the president's
sending troops into your city. It feels
like it's turned into a banana republic.
>> And a lot of very smart people have
begun making comparisons to the summer
of 68. And that's not something you want
to be compared to.
>> No.
No.
>> Dang.
>> Mhm.
>> Well, John, what sort of advice do you
have for Americans right now going
forward?
>> You know, I think all Americans should
be involved in the political process. I
really do.
>> Do you still have hope in the political
process?
>> Yeah. Saying that,
>> crazy as it sounds, you have optimism. I
I [snorts] am I'm optimistic. I I make a
joke frequently on my own podcast that
I'm an equal opportunity hater. I hate
everybody.
>> Yeah. Right. Um, [laughter]
>> that's great.
Real libertarian. Real
>> I really am a libertarian. I truly am.
>> Um,
but I see hope in individuals. I believe
very strongly that we need viable third
parties very strongly. In 2016,
I was uh very fortunate to travel with
Governor Gary Johnson to 12 states out
west and I introduced him at all of his
campaign stops.
>> That's cool. Yeah, we got 2.8%.
Which was a record. One of those was
mine. Yeah.
>> Yay. Awesome. I wasn't allowed to vote
yet, but uh
>> otherwise I would. I voted for him in
2012.
>> All right.
>> Yeah. I didn't vote for that criminal
Obama.
>> But um
we need a viable Libertarian party and
we need a viable Green Party. or even,
you know, I keep getting these emails
from something called the uh
it's not the reform party, it's the uh
>> I'm not sure.
>> Um I don't I I just delete them. But
it's supposed to be this this
moderate Yeah. this middle of the road
party.
>> Oh, yeah. You know what I'm talking
about? Yeah,
>> I forget what they call themselves,
but one of the lessons that I learned
with the libertarians,
I'll tell you a funny story first. I was
invited to the Libertarian Christmas
party, Christmas of 2016. So, being
libertarians, it wasn't held until the
end of January, of course, [laughter]
because nobody can get their act
together.
>> And that's why we don't have a third
party.
>> This is like January 23rd. I'm going to
the Christmas party. It was over here in
Alexandria.
and we all had hello, my name is name
tags on. So this guy looks at my name
tag and he goes, "John Keryaku, I've
been looking all over for you and I look
at his and and he's the head of the
Virginia Libertarian Party." I said, "Oh
yeah, I've heard of you. Nice to meet
you." We were CCed on a couple of emails
together. Nice to meet you. And he goes,
"I want to ask you, would you run for
governor of Virginia?" And I said,
"Absolutely not."
>> Wow. And he said, "Not why not." I said,
"Listen, I like you guys a lot. I really
do. And I believe in the Libertarian
Party, but first of all, nobody has his
act together. This party's a month
overdue.
>> This party is January 23rd."
>> Yeah. [laughter] And I said, and I said,
"I know that you guys mean well, but I
know it's going to happen. I'll register
to run as a Libertarian. You guys are
going to all forget all about me. I'm
going to be completely out of pocket.
I'm gonna go broke and then I'm going to
get 1% and I'm going to humiliate
myself. I said, "No thanks." Well, he
said, "Well, okay. I I get it. I get
it." Because it was true. All of it was
true. So, when we were we were traveling
around the West, we went to like Alaska,
Washington, Oregon, Utah. We went all
over the place. It was so much fun. We
bought this beaten up old Winnebago for
like $36,000.
>> Yeah. And um and except for we we flew
to Alaska, but everywhere else we just
drove all over the place. So, one of the
things I learned was that the
Libertarian Party doesn't have a major
donor, right? There was this one guy
that they only referred to as the canned
tomato king of California. I don't know
who that is. Um he's a libertarian and
he gave them $40,000,
which was a lot by libertarian
standards. And they used it to buy the
Winnebago. [laughter]
>> The entire Libertarian Party is equal
the value of one Winnebago United
States.
>> It was lovely. It was nice. Up, but the
sides, [laughter]
you know, popped out so you had extra
room when you parked. It was okay. The
>> slides. Yeah, the slides. Get all six
voters in there.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
But, you know, you've got for both
Democrats and Republicans, people giving
millions and millions of dollars at a
time. You know, the Adlesen's would just
write checks for millions of dollars.
And these Hollywood mucky mucks, they'll
have a a a dinner at, you know, some
producers's house and raise $50 million.
And the libertarians can't compete with
that. And then the Greens are just
>> Yeah.
>> You know, God bless them. They're most
of them are lovely people. the ones that
I have met, but they're just not
>> no chance
>> not serious people.
>> Well, the math doesn't really sustain a
third party in our country because we
have first passed the post and a 50%
plus one vote. If you do the math, it's
just impossible. You can't win.
>> You have to buddy up with some unless
you win 8% of the vote and then you get
8% of the representation. Now, it's now
that that is a way to climb into the
ranks and get proper but but if you have
to win 50% plus one, you have to make a
deal with one of the two big parties.
And I mean they've run this in game
theory in scenarios in colleges
everywhere where you have 10 parties and
they just start going and after four
elections it's two parties. It just it
always consolidates
>> right. In Greece I follow Greek politics
very very closely. Parties are
constantly coming and going. Right. But
the winners are always one of two.
>> And the one of them kind of changes its
name every once in a while but it's just
these two.
>> Yeah. And it's it's in the design of the
rules. You have to actually change the
rules, I think, to to enable third
parties to get into.
>> 100 years ago, we had a whole bunch of
parties. Yeah.
>> Right. We had a a viable socialist
party. We had [snorts] we had the
Progressive Party. Yeah. A little
farther back, the Wig Party. We had all
kinds of different parties. And they
were getting people elected to Congress.
But one thing that the libertarians just
get wrong and I said this too at the
time
as if it were my place to say it like
let me tell you guys how you should run
your party. [laughter]
Just listen to this. I said I get these
hair on fire emails from you guys and
they're like oh my god we just elected a
guy to the water board of Milwaukee.
And people are like awesome.
Okay. And then you don't run anybody
else in any of those other races and
then you run for president. What are you
doing?
>> Yeah.
>> Something like 70% of all races at at
every level are unopposed.
So you can run for every waterboard
position, every schoolboard position,
half of the legis state legislative
races. You can get a ton of people
elected as libertarians
if you wanted to.
>> Wow.
>> And I don't think they want to.
>> That's amazing.
>> It's a lot of work involved.
>> It's a lot of work.
>> Yeah.
>> You got to wake up every day.
>> I'll tell you one other story. We were
in uh
we flew from um Anchorage to Juno. Gary
was going to do a uh a speech at the
University of Alaska at Juno. and a guy
who had been like the Libertarian
nominee for vice president from 1992
or 96, I forget. I remember he was a
State Farm agent. He was flying up from
Texas.
Um, and he was going to meet us at the
airport. Like his flight from Seattle,
he went from Dallas to Seattle, Seattle
to Juno. It was going to arrive at the
same time that ours did. So, we're
supposed to pick him up and take him to
the hotel and then from the hotel to the
venue.
So, we all fly in. It was like eight of
us. We fly in from from Anchorage and
we're waiting for him and waiting for
him. And Juno airport, if you've ever
been to Juno, it's like the size of this
room. It's like gate one is there, gate
two is there, there's three, there's
four. That's the whole airport. It's
right here. And there's a Starbucks.
That's it. So, we're waiting for him.
We're looking around like it's the eight
of us and there's nobody else and we
don't see him. So, we page him. I said
to one of the interns, "Do you mind uh
paging this guy? Here's his name." They
page him. Please meet your party at uh
you know, gate one. Nothing. So, we
paged him a second time. Nothing. So, we
go to the hotel and we said, "Did he did
he get past us and he got to the hotel
first?" And they said, "No, he hasn't
checked in yet." So, it came time I said
to Gary, "We really should go to the
venue now. We're going to be late." So,
we got in our vans and we drove to the
venue. I introduced Gary. He starts
speaking and then the guy shows up and I
said, "Where have you been?" He said, "I
was waiting for you guys." I said,
"Where?" He said, "At the airport." I
said, "Didn't you hear us page you?" He
goes, "I heard somebody page me. I
figured it's probably NSA tracking my
movements. [laughter]
>> And I said, "And that is why this party
will never turn into anything." That's
what I said to him. That's all I said to
him. I was so angry.
>> That is wild. Well, they're paranoid,
but it's it's almost like if you were at
the top, you have you have to be
paranoid. These guys are getting sued
over everything nowadays. You have to
have deep pockets.
>> Yeah, you do. Which kind of makes me
wonder, do you think Trump could go for
a third term just because he seems to be
a guy that can fight off lawsuits
constantly?
>> I don't. I think he's just having a
blast
>> just overwhelming
>> toying with the Democrats.
>> And of course, they lose their minds
every time he says something like this.
No, I I don't think Yeah. You know, the
guy's almost 80 years old now. I think I
mean, what more could he possibly
accomplish in life,
>> right?
>> So, no, I think he's just having fun.
>> That's good news. Yeah. Yeah. We don't
want to break precedent here.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No.
>> And the only way you could do it is
probably to be in wartime, actually.
Isn't
>> I I don't think you could even do it
then.
>> Okay.
>> I really don't.
>> That's great. I think that's probably
what a lot of people are nervous about
in the back of their minds, but it seems
I agree with you. I don't know why he
would.
>> He's getting older. I mean, even just as
a human,
>> what do you you know, you did a lot. And
you know, if he wanted to leave a
legacy, he's [snorts] succeeded.
I don't think he had success. I don't
think he successfully created a legacy
after the first term,
>> right?
>> I think it was kind of chaotic, but
after this one, Yeah. I mean, he's got
genuine,
>> what should we call them? Uh,
>> he's a
>> mentees.
>> Yeah.
The word is slipping my mind right now.
It's uh
>> when
>> what did you say?
>> Accolades.
>> Kind of success.
>> Successors. Yeah. Accolades.
>> Oh, successors.
>> Yeah.
>> He's got people. He's got Dr. Oz up
there. Yeah.
>> Yeah. You know, I don't think that he
has permanently changed the Republican
party. I think that at its heart, the
Republican party is a neoconservative
party just like the Democrats are a
neoliberal party. But otherwise, you
know, he gave he gave populism a shot in
the arm that we haven't seen since the
30s. Really? Do you think it was it was
needed or it was it was overdone?
>> He's a controversial figure.
>> I don't want to criticize.
>> Yeah, that's fair.
>> Well, John, I think it's I think we're
up. Our time is about up. It's been a
real pleasure chatting with you, man. in
person.
>> Yeah.
>> Good. Good to see you in person.
>> Yeah. Great to meet you in person
finally. Thank you.
>> Yeah, this is great. Thanks for coming
on the show.
>> Thanks for the invitation.
>> All right. Thanks everybody.